

Objective

To have a growth oriented and challenging career, where I can contribute my knowledge and skills to the organization and enhance my experience through continuous learning and teamwork. Also, I'm willing to learn new skills that would prove to be useful for me and for the organization in the future.

ARJUN SHARMA

SEO & CONTENT EXPERT

Professional Experience

Esthetic Centers Int. Pvt Ltd | SEO & Content Manager

July 2024 - Jan'25

Key responsibilities:

 Looking after the overall SEO of the project from site audits to creating wireframe layouts for the new website to writing SEO optimized contents.

RankUno Interactive Technologies | Senior SEO Analyst

June 2023 - June 2024

Key responsibilities:

- Carry out On Page & Off Page SEO
- Increase organic traffic on the websites
- Creating wireframe layouts
- Writing (SEO Optimized) Blogs & Articles for the clients' websites.
- Competitor research and technical audits and increasing keyword rankings

Hummingbird Web Solutions | Digital Marketing Executive

March 2022 - June 2023

Key responsibilities:

- Carry out On Page & Off Page SEO
- Increase organic traffic on the websites
- · Email marketing
- Writing (SEO Optimized) Blogs & Articles for the websites.
- Creating Deal Pages for the ecommerce websites.

Vajiram & Ravi | Content Writer Drishti IAS | Evaluator

Oct 2020 - Feb 2022

- Worked as a Content Developer at Vajiram & Ravi, contributing to the creation of high-quality educational content.
- Served as an evaluator for UPSC mains answer scripts at Drishti IAS, providing constructive feedback to students.

Fitternity Health Solutions, Mumbai | Vendor Manager in Business & Operations

Sep 2019- Sep 2020

 Worked as a junior associate and then was promoted as a Relationship Manager in Vendor Management and Business and Operations Team at Fitternity Health Solutions Pvt Ltd, Mumbai. (From Sep 2019 – Dec 2020)

My Contact

sharma.arjunbalkavi@gmail.com

+91-8275837451

Janki Niwas, Deopeth, Washim - 444505

http://readwritewords.co.in/

Hard Skills

- Content (Blog/Article) Writing
- SEO (On Page & Off Page)
- Email Marketing
- Creating Deal Pages for E-commerce Sites

Soft Skills

- Creative & innovative thought process
- Good Decision-making power
- Good English communication skills
- · Multi-tasking
- · Strong work ethics

Education Background

SSC

Amravati Divisional Board - 82% Completed in 2011

HSC

Board of Intermediate Education, Andhra Pradesh - 79.04%

Completed in 2013

 Bachelor of Engineering (CSE)
 Sant Gadge Baba Amravati University -73.11%

2015 - 2019

 MBA (Yashwantrao Chavan Maharashtra Open University)
 9.09 / 10 CGPA
 2021–2024

Achievements

- Got rewarded as Performer of the Month for increasing organic traffic by implementing SEO Strategies and publishing well structured and optimized blogs, in Hummingbird Web Solutions
- Got promoted as a Team Leader in just 4 months at Fitternity Health Solutions Pvt Ltd, Mumbai
- Earned a monetary reward of ₹28,000 for successfully executing SEO campaigns and achieving significant improvements in keyword rankings, primarily through blogs created by me. The campaigns were delivered for three clients, including two from the United States and one from India
- Achieved a significant milestone in October 2024 by surpassing the projected traffic numbers, reaching the highest level in over a year

Tools I Use:

- Tools I Use To Bring Out The Best Results
- Ahrefs
 - a) For Competitor Analysis
 - b) To find out the best possible sources to get backlinks from
 - c) To look for relevant keywords (long and short tail)
- Google Search Console To monitor and trach websites overall presence on the SERP
- MOZ

To see the authority of any website and get insights on increasing the score of the site

Answer The Public -

To get an idea as to what the people in the specific region are looking for related to my topic

- Google Trends To check how trending is any specific keyword
- GT Metrix -

To look after some essential things like website loading time, performance, etc

• SEMRush -

To check search volumes and see keyword recommendations, competitor analysis, toxic backlink analysis, etc

SE Ranking -

To include and monitor the keyword rankings and to carry out the technical analysis of the website

- Dataslayer
 Translation of a section (a section for a section for
 - To gather data of a website for any duration required at once
- Google (Ads) Keyword Planner To see for keyword ideas, keyword volumes and priority
- Google Analytics 4 (GA4) -

To maintain a daily report of the website(s) in regards with the session/traffic, conversions (Organic & Overall)

- Screaming Frog
 - a) To analyze the website for erros.
- b) To list out all the H Tags, Meta Tags whenever required for the pages
- Neuron Writer -

To beat the competitor score by including necessary keywords in the content